Colin Nebula

Contract

Woodbridge, ON L4L 8Y9 colinnebula@gmail.com +1 416 856 5764

IT Technical Support: Dealing with customers in a professional manner while tending to their technological needs efficiently, has been a mainstay in my job description for over a decade. Troubleshooting, reporting bugs, investigating, designing, and performing product tests were daily requirements at my previous full-time job at Tira Wireless where I also gained deep insight into the development cycle of software.

Currently, I provide a comprehensive array of technical services that generally involve managing issues and problem-solving, and then addressing the root causes to implement preventative strategies for the future. Setting benchmarks, maintaining licenses, and creating guidelines are other areas I have contributed to, in both my full and part-time jobs.

I am a recent graduate of the University of Toronto's coding Bootcamp with a new set of skills as a Full Stack Web Developer. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React, SQL, Express.js, and Bootstrap are among some of my acquired skills.

Work Experience

Creative Director

Nebula Media - Woodbridge, ON August 2013 to September 2021

- A host of responsibilities including but not limited to overseeing video production, 3D integration, and video editing
- Discussed, planned, executed, and met client requirements including timely deadlines.
- Primarily used Adobe and Blender
- Worked independently mostly and remotely for clients dispersed over Canada

Modeler and Texture Artist

Marvimation - Ontario July 2011 to June 2012

- 3D Modeling position using Adobe After Effects
- Modeling objects for 3D integration through live action using Blender.

Internship

Intelligent Creatures April 2010 to August 2010

- Worked on MODELLING, TEXTURING, ROTO-SCOPING for feature pilot projects
- · Rotoscoping and lens grid distortions were some of the skills that were mainly honed
- Used Nuke, Maya, 3D Max

Quality Assurance - Mobile Game Platform

Tira Wireless - Ontario August 2007 to July 2008

- Tested and logged bugs, addressing issues through the JIRA workflow manager, conducted field tests, and regressions, developed strategies to reduce redundancies, and completed general QA duties such as running reports and assisting the team in hitting weekly targets.
- Set up a rotating schedule to improve team efficiency by assigning equipment for specific periods to each team member to reduce dead time and exceed weekly testing targets
- Clients included companies such as Sony, ING, Hudson Soft, THQ, and AccuWeather, each with specific demands and multiple unique requests to account for in testing scenarios.

Technical Support-Inbound Call Centre

Epson Printing - Richmond Hill, ON December 2003 to January 2005

- Provided troubleshooting for the complete product line, resolved complaints, and ordered replacements for customers in a timely manner while up-selling other Epson products
- Conducted weekly reports, solved issues through rigorous testing that required multi-department input, and introduced ideas such as empowering the group with more tools to resolve complaints
- Managed customer concerns with sensitivity and followed company policy on assessing claims, returns, or repairs
- · Maintained top performance numbers for accuracy and commended for punctuality

Computer Technician

Advanced Brake Products - Ontario June 2003 to August 2004

- Set up multiple office computers and connected them to the network to share office resources such as inventory systems, billings, production, and multiple sets of printers
- Provided considerable support in training and preparing staff for tasks on the new systems as well as set up security to prevent damage or loss of valuable information
- Performed routine tasks to keep the network and individual workstations problem-free and was responsible for all software and hardware issues experienced by staff

Education

AEC / DEP or Skilled Trade Certificate in Web Development

University Of Toronto Coding Bootcamp - Ontario

May 2021 to November 2021

Skills

- Adobe After Effects (8 years)
- Maya (6 years)
- Adobe Illustrator (10+ years)
- 3D Animation (10+ years)
- Graphic Design (8 years)

- Adobe Photoshop (10+ years)
- Web Design (6 years)
- 3D S Max
- HTML5 (2 years)
- CSS (2 years)
- React (2 years)
- Node.js (2 years)
- Bootstrap (2 years)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- Responsive Design (2 years)
- AJAX (2 years)
- DOM (2 years)
- SQL (2 years)
- GitHub (2 years)
- REST
- Jira
- MySQL
- Redux
- MongoDB
- JSON
- Java
- APIs
- MVC
- Web Services

Links

http://colinnebula3dartist.blogspot.ca/

https://colinnebula.github.io/colin-react-portfolio/

Military Service

Branch: Field ArtilleryService Country: United States

Rank: Specialist

May 1995 to May 2000

Certifications and Licenses

Full Stack Web Developer

May 2021 to Present

- Front end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Handlebars, and React are only some examples of areas of focus and training as exemplified through successful completion of team and individual projects
- Back end: GraphQL, MongoDB, MySQL, SQL, Node.js, Express.js, and Mongoose are some examples of key areas of study and application
- Creating and combining back-end and front-end web applications in a very short time frame to meet deadlines
- Using GitHub to store different versions of the project through the Git workflow.
- Collaborating with peers through zoom to create projects with proper team management, cohesion, and direction to complete big projects within a tight time frame

Additional Information

Web Development
HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
AJAX, Bootstrap, Rest, MongoDB, SQL
jQuery, Git
Responsive Design,
DOM, Node.js, Express.js,
Object Relational Mapping(ORM)
React, Redux

Graphic Design

SOFTWARE Maya, 3DS Max, Photoshop, After Effects, Nuke Zbrush, Fusion, xNormal, Premiere Pro, Illustrator, PF Track.
ART Modelling and Texturing Characters, Props, and Backgrounds ANIMATION Detailed knowledge of Animation with regard to form and motion.

TECHNICAL Character Rigging, Lighting, and Visual Effects.

COMPOSITING Experience in Film editing and manipulation such as Tracking and Rotoscoping using Nuke.